<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> 
<Topics>


<Topic name="Node.Clone(bool,INodeCloningListener)">
<summary>
Creates a duplicate of the node.
</summary>
<remarks><p>This method serves as a copy constructor for nodes. 
The cloned node has no parent, but belongs to the same document as the original node.</p>
<p>This method always performs a deep copy of the node. The <paramref name="isCloneChildren"/> parameter
specifies whether to perform copy all child nodes as well.</p>
</remarks>
<param name="isCloneChildren">True to recursively clone the subtree under the specified node; 
false to clone only the node itself.</param>
<param name="cloningListener">Listener to node cloning event.</param>
<returns>The cloned node.</returns>
</Topic>

<Topic name="Node.Clone(bool)">
<summary>
Creates a duplicate of the node.
</summary>
<remarks><p>This method serves as a copy constructor for nodes. 
The cloned node has no parent, but belongs to the same document as the original node.</p>
<p>This method always performs a deep copy of the node. The <paramref name="isCloneChildren"/> parameter
specifies whether to perform copy all child nodes as well.</p>
</remarks>
<param name="isCloneChildren">True to recursively clone the subtree under the specified node; 
false to clone only the node itself.</param>
<returns>The cloned node.</returns>
</Topic>


<Topic name="Node.Accept">
<summary>
Accepts a visitor.
</summary>
<remarks>
<p>Enumerates over this node and all of its children. Each node calls a corresponding method on <see cref="DocumentVisitor"/>.</p>
<p>For more info see the Visitor design pattern.</p>
</remarks>
<param name="visitor">The visitor that will visit the nodes.</param>
<returns>True if all nodes were visited; false if <see cref="DocumentVisitor"/> stopped the operation before visiting all nodes.</returns>
</Topic>


<Topic name="CompositeNode.InsertCommon">
<remarks>
<p>If the <paramref name="newChild"/> is already in the tree, it is first removed.</p>
<p>If the node being inserted was created from another document, you should use 
<see cref="Aspose.Words.DocumentBase.ImportNode(Node, bool, ImportFormatMode)"/> to import the node to the current document. 
The imported node can then be inserted into the current document.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>
  
  
<Topic name="NodeCollection.InsertCommon">
<remarks>
<p>If the node being inserted was created from another document, you should use 
<see cref="Aspose.Words.DocumentBase.ImportNode(Node, bool, ImportFormatMode)"/> to import the node to the current document. 
The imported node can then be inserted into the current document.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>


<Topic name="NodeCollection.IndexerCommon">
<remarks>
<p>The index is zero-based.</p>
<p>Negative indexes are allowed and indicate access from the back of the collection. 
For example -1 means the last item, -2 means the second before last and so on.</p>
<p>If index is greater than or equal to the number of items in the list, this returns a null reference.</p>
<p>If index is negative and its absolute value is greater than the number of items in the list, this returns a null reference.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>


<Topic name="NodeCollection.ToArrayCommon">
<p>You should not be adding/removing nodes while iterating over a collection 
of nodes because it invalidates the iterator and requires refreshes for live collections.</p>
<p>To be able to add/remove nodes during iteration, use this method to copy 
nodes into a fixed-size array and then iterate over the array.</p>
</Topic>


<Topic name="CompositeNode.GetChildNodesLive">
<remarks>
<p>A live collection is always in sync with the document. For example, if you
selected all sections in a document and enumerate through the collection
deleting the sections, the section is removed from the collection immediately
when it is removed from the document.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>


<Topic name="Document.Clone">
<summary>
Creates a duplicate of the document.
</summary>
<remarks>
<p>
If you need to generate many documents from a single document,
just load the document into memory once, clone it and populate the cloned
document with your data. This speeds up generation of documents because there is
no need to load and parse the document from file every time.
</p>
</remarks>
<param name="isCloneChildren">
True to recursively clone the content of the document;
false to clone only the document node and document-wide objects such as styles and lists.
</param>
<returns>The cloned document.</returns>
</Topic>

<Topic name="Document.ImportNodeCommon">
  <p>Importing a node creates a copy of the source node belonging to the importing document. 
The returned node has no parent. The source node is not altered or removed from the original document.</p>
<p>Before a node from another document can be inserted into this document, it must be imported.
During import, document-specific properties such as references to styles and lists are translated
from the original to the importing document. After the node was imported, it can be inserted
into the appropriate place in the document using <see cref="CompositeNode.InsertBefore{T}(T, Node)"/> or 
<see cref="CompositeNode.InsertAfter{T}(T, Node)"/>.</p>
<p>If the source node already belongs to the destination document, then simply a deep clone
of the source node is created.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic name="Document.OpenStreamCommon">
<remarks>
<p>
  The document must be stored at the beginning of the stream. <ms>The stream must support random positioning.</ms><cpp>The stream must support random positioning.</cpp>
</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>

<Topic name="Document.LoadFileExceptions">
  <exception cref="UnsupportedFileFormatException">The document format is not recognized or not supported.</exception>
  <exception cref="FileCorruptedException">The document appears to be corrupted and cannot be loaded.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.Exception">There is a problem with the document and it should be reported to Aspose.Words developers.</exception>
  <exception cref="IOException">There is an input/output exception.</exception>
  <exception cref="IncorrectPasswordException">The document is encrypted and requires a password to open, but you supplied an incorrect password.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.ArgumentException">The name of the file cannot be null or empty string.</exception>
</Topic>

<Topic name="Document.LoadStreamExceptions">
  <exception cref="UnsupportedFileFormatException">The document format is not recognized or not supported.</exception>
  <exception cref="FileCorruptedException">The document appears to be corrupted and cannot be loaded.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.Exception">There is a problem with the document and it should be reported to Aspose.Words developers.</exception>
  <exception cref="IOException">There is an input/output exception.</exception>
  <exception cref="IncorrectPasswordException">The document is encrypted and requires a password to open, but you supplied an incorrect password.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.ArgumentNullException">The stream cannot be null.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.NotSupportedException">The stream does not support reading or seeking.</exception>
  <exception cref="System.ObjectDisposedException">The stream is a disposed object.</exception>
</Topic>



<Topic name="ParagraphFormat.AutoSpacing">
<remarks>
<p>When you set paragraph Space Before and Space After to Auto,
Microsoft Word adds 14 points spacing between paragraphs automatically
according to the following rules:</p>
<list type="bullet">
<item>Normally, spacing is added after all paragraphs.</item>
<item>In a bulleted or numbered list, spacing is added only after the last item in the list.
Spacing is not added between the list items.</item>
<item>In a nested bulleted or numbered list spacing is not added.</item>
<item>Spacing is normally added after a table.</item>
<item>Spacing is not added after a table if it is the last block in a table cell.</item>
<item>Spacing is not added after the last paragraph in a table cell.</item>
</list>
</remarks>
</Topic>


<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertImageCommon">
<p>You can change the image size, location, positioning method and other settings using the 
<see cref="Aspose.Words.Drawing.Shape"/> object returned by this method.</p>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertJavaBufferedImage">
<java>
<p>Aspose.Words will insert the image in the PNG format and with default settings. If you want to insert a <tt>BufferedImage</tt> in 
another format or with other settings, you need to save the image into a byte array and use <see cref="InsertImage(byte[])"/>.</p>
</java>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertImageParams">
<param name="width">The width of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</param>
<param name="height">The height of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</param>
<returns>The image node that was just inserted.</returns>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertImageJavaParams">
<javaParam name="width">The width of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="height">The height of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</javaParam>
<returns>The image node that was just inserted.</returns>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertImageParamsEx">
<param name="horzPos">Specifies where the distance to the image is measured from.</param>
<param name="left">Distance in points from the origin to the left side of the image.</param>
<param name="vertPos">Specifies where the distance to the image measured from.</param>
<param name="top">Distance in points from the origin to the top side of the image.</param>
<param name="width">The width of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</param>
<param name="height">The height of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</param>
<param name="wrapType">Specifies how to wrap text around the image.</param>
<returns>The image node that was just inserted.</returns>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentBuilder.InsertImageJavaParamsEx">
<javaParam name="horzPos">A <see cref="RelativeHorizontalPosition"/> value. Specifies where the distance to the image is measured from.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="left">Distance in points from the origin to the left side of the image.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="vertPos">A <see cref="RelativeVerticalPosition"/> value. Specifies where the distance to the image measured from.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="top">Distance in points from the origin to the top side of the image.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="width">The width of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="height">The height of the image in points. Can be a negative or zero value to request 100% scale.</javaParam>
<javaParam name="wrapType">A <see cref="WrapType"/> value. Specifies how to wrap text around the image.</javaParam>
<returns>The image node that was just inserted.</returns>
</Topic>


<Topic name="DocumentProperties.Common">
<remarks>
<p>The names of the properties are case-insensitive.</p>
<p>The properties in the collection are sorted alphabetically by name.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>

<Topic name="DocumentProperties.JavaSlow">
<remarks>
<p><b>Note: </b>In Java this method is slow because iterates over all nodes.</p>
</remarks>
</Topic>


<Topic name="IsInsertRevision">
<summary>
Returns true if this object was inserted in Microsoft Word while change tracking was enabled.
</summary>
</Topic>

<Topic name="IsDeleteRevision">
<summary>
Returns true if this object was deleted in Microsoft Word while change tracking was enabled.
</summary>
</Topic>

<Topic name="IsFormatRevision">
<summary>
Returns true if formatting of the object was changed in Microsoft Word while change tracking was enabled.
</summary>
</Topic>

<Topic name="IsMoveFromRevision">
<summary>
Returns <c>true</c> if this object was moved (deleted) in Microsoft Word while change tracking was enabled.
</summary>
</Topic>

<Topic name="IsMoveToRevision">
<summary>
Returns <c>true</c> if this object was moved (inserted) in Microsoft Word while change tracking was enabled.
</summary>
</Topic>


<Topic name="Field.Common">
<p>A complete field in a Microsoft Word document is a complex structure consisting of
a field start character, field code, field separator character, field result
and field end character. Some fields only have field start, field code and field end.</p>
<p>To easily insert a new field into a document, use the <see cref="DocumentBuilder.InsertField(string)"/>
method.</p>
</Topic>

  
<Topic name="UpdateFields"  >
<para>When you open, modify and then save a document, Aspose.Words does not update fields automatically, it keeps them intact.
Therefore, you would usually want to call this method before saving if you have modified the document
programmatically and want to make sure the proper (calculated) field values appear in the saved document.</para>
<para>There is no need to update fields after executing a mail merge because mail merge is a kind of field update
and automatically updates all fields in the document.</para>
<p>This method does not update all field types. For the detailed list of supported field types, see the Programmers Guide.</p>
<para>This method does not update fields that are related to the page layout algorithms (e.g. PAGE, PAGES, PAGEREF).
In the Aspose.Words FOSS version these fields are never updated.</para>
</Topic>


<Topic name="GlossaryDocument.NotVisited">
<remarks>
<para>
Note: A glossary document node and its children are not visited when you execute a
Visitor over a <see cref="Aspose.Words.Document"/>. If you want to execute a Visitor over a
glossary document, you need to call <see cref="GlossaryDocument.Accept"/>.
</para>
</remarks>
</Topic>

<Topic name="BuildingBlock.NotVisited">
<remarks>
<para>
Note: A building block node and its children are not visited when you execute a
Visitor over a <see cref="Aspose.Words.Document"/>. If you want to execute a Visitor over a
building block, you need to execute the visitor over <see cref="GlossaryDocument"/> or
call <see cref="BuildingBlock.Accept"/>.
</para>
</remarks>
</Topic>

<Topic name="SaveOptions.HtmlExportFontResourcesCommonLicensingWarning">
<p>
  <b>Important!</b> When exporting font resources, font licensing issues should be considered. Authors who want to use specific fonts via a downloadable
  font mechanism must always carefully verify that their intended use is within the scope of the font license. Many commercial fonts presently do not
  allow web downloading of their fonts in any form. License agreements that cover some fonts specifically note that usage via <b>@font-face</b> rules
  in CSS style sheets is not allowed. Font subsetting can also violate license terms.
</p>
</Topic>


</Topics>
